Rider, look.
ライダー あれ
Are you scared, boy?
怖いか 坊主
Yeah. I'm scared.
ああ 怖いね
Or should I borrow your words and say this is exciting?
それともこういうの
お前流に言うなら「心が躍る」ってやつなのかな
貴様もわきまえてきたではないか
Seems like you're starting to understand.
敵は中か
Is the enemy inside?
Berserker?!
バーサーカー
Utw
Presents
Will one last miracle come to pass?
あと一度だけ奇跡は起こるだろう
Ato ichido dake kiseki wa okoru darou
A gentle voice paints a twisted future
優しい声で描く歪んだ未来
Yasashii koe de egaku yuganda mirai
For the sake of a world where nobody will cry
もう誰も泣かない世界の為に
Mou dare mo nakanai sekai no tame ni
Before reaching the crimson-stained sky
紅く汚された空の何処にも
Akaku kegasareta sora no doko ni mo
My cries and prayers fade and disappear
届かず消える叫びと祈り
Todokazu kieru sakebi to inori
I can go on, abandoning all consolation
慰めは捨てて行ける
Nagusame wa sutete yukeru
The beautiful moonlight shines towards the beginning and vanishes
綺麗な月の光が始まりへと沈み行く
Kirei na tsuki no hikari ga hajimari e to shizumiyuku
Into the distance
その彼方へ
Sono kanata e
I'll continue to reach out as my eyes are gradually closed
閉ざされてく瞳でまだ遠くへ手を伸ばす
Tozasareteku hitomi de mada tooku e te wo nobasu
I believe in your sorrow
君の嘆きを 信じて
Kimi no nageki wo shinjite
They're going to drink here?
ここで酒宴を始める気か
What happened to your beloved chariot?
自慢の戦車はどうした
Well...
ああ それな
It irks me to say this, but I lost it to Saber.
業腹ながらセイバーのやつに持って行かれてなあ
Have you forgotten what I had decided?
オレの決定を忘れたか
I believe I told you I'd defeat you at your full strength.
貴様は万全な状態で倒すものと告げておいたはずだが
True, my weapons have been somewhat depleted.
確かに余の武装は消耗しておる
だが
However...
今宵のイスカンダルは
It is because I am not in perfect condition that I am more than perfect tonight.
完壁ではないが故に「完壁以上」なのだ
I see.
なるほど
Indeed, the aura that you're exuding...
たしかに充溢するその王気
It's more potent than usual.
いつになく強壮だ
It appears you've come here with some chance of winning.
どうやら何の勝算もなくオレの前に立ったわけでもないらしい
バビロニアの王よ
King of Babylonia, a final word.
最後に一つ 宴の締めの問答だ
Our banquet's last question.
許す 述べるがよい
I shall allow it. Speak.
Now, if my Ionian Hetairoi were armed using your Gate of Babylon,
たとえばな 余の「王の軍勢」を貴様の「王の財宝」で武装させれば
間違いなく最強の兵団が出来上がる
it would surely create the most powerful army imaginable.
And?
それで
Why don't we become allies?
改めて 余の盟友とならんか
Together, the two of us could conquer the stars themselves.
我ら二人が結べば きっと星々の果てまで征服できるぞ
つくづく愉快な奴よ
You never cease to amuse me.
道化でもない奴の痴れ言でここまで笑ったのは久方ぶりだ
It's been so long since I've laughed this hard
at the ramblings of someone who isn't a fool.
あいにくだがな
Unfortunately, there is only one friend that I've had and ever will have.
我が朋友は後にも先にもただ一人のみ
Also, there is no need for two kings.
そして 王たる者もまた二人は必要ない
孤高なる王道か
The lonely path of kingship.
I shall challenge your unwavering spirit with respect.
その揺るがぬ在りように 余は敬服をもって挑むとしよう
Very well.
良い 存分に己を示せよ征服王
Show me what you can do, King of Conquerors.
お前はオレが審判するにあたう賊だ
You are a rebel worthy of my judgment.
You guys seem friendly with each other.
オマエら 本当は仲がいいのか
邪険にできるはずもなかろうよ
I could hardly be unfriendly to him.
He may well be the last opponent I'll face.
余が生涯最後に視線を交わす相手になるかもしれんのだ
馬鹿いうなよ
Don't be stupid.
お前が殺されるわけないだろ
You can't possibly be killed.
I won't allow it.
承知しないぞ
僕の令呪を忘れたか
Have you forgotten about my Command Spells?!
そうだな
You're right.
You're exactly right!
その通りだとも
Gather, my comrades!
集えよ 我が同胞
今宵 我らは最強の伝説に勇姿を記す
Tonight, we go down as the greatest legend in history!
Our enemy is the mighty King of Heroes.
敵は万夫不当の英雄王
相手にとって不足なし
A worthy opponent!
My warriors, let us show the eldest
Heroic Spirit our path of conquest!
いざ益猛男たちよ 原初の英霊に我らが覇道を示そうぞ
Come to me, leader of conquering armies.
来るがいい 覇軍の主よ
You will now behold the form of a true king.
今こそお前は真の王者の姿を知るのだ
Why are you in so much pain?
どうして そんなに苦しむの
バーサーカーは 戦わなければならないからだ
Because Berserker... must fight...
なんで
Why?
あの神父がそう言っていたから
Because the priest said so.
神父さんは
The priest?
ああ 約束してくれたんだ
Yeah.
He promised me that he'd give me the Grail.
オレに聖杯を渡すって
聖杯さえあれば君を救える
Once I have the Grail, I can save you.
助けてくれるの
You're going to save me?
ああ 約束したろ
Yeah, I promised you...
That we'd all play together... like we used to.
また皆で昔みたいに一緒に遊ぼうって
じゃ またお母さんに会えるのね
Then...
I'll be able to see Mom again, right?
お母さん
Mom...?
Now!
今だ
It barely scratched him?!
浅い
見えてる
He can see it?
He knows the length of this blade.
この剣の間合を知っている
ヤツは私に縁のあるの騎士なのか
Could he be a knight I once knew?
その武練 さぞや名のある騎士と見込んだ上で
I assume from your skill that you are a famous knight, and ask you this.
問わせてもらう
この私をブリテン王アルトリア·ペンドラゴンとわきまえた上で挑むなら
If you know me to be Arturia Pendragon, King of Britain,
騎士たる者の誇りをもって その来歴を明かすがいい
reveal who you are, as a knight's pride demands!
Attacking with your identity hidden amounts to foul play!
素性を伏せたまま挑みかかるのは騙し討ちにも等しいぞ
貴様
You...
N-No...
そ そんな
A-Arondight?
無毀なる湖光
まさか 貴方は
You can't be...
Arthur...
アーサー
Sir Lancelot...
サー·ランスロット
何故だ 友よ
Why, my friend?
You were the first of the Knights of the Round Table!
円卓の騎士の内でも第一と称されたほどの貴方が何故
Why would you sink so low as to become Berserker-
バーサーカーに落ちてまで
Lancelot!
ランスロット
Lancelot...
貴様は臣下を「救う」ばかりで 「導く」ことをしなかった
You saved your subjects, but you never led them.
「導く」ことをしなかったから
Because I never led them...
You are bound by the false idol of a king who serves others but not himself...
人の為の「王」という偶像に縛られていただけの
My ideals...
私の理想が
私という王が
My kingship...
小娘にすぎん
You are but a little girl.
Have they driven you to this state?!
貴方をそんなにも追い詰めてしまったのか
Arthur!
アーサー
ランスロット
Lancelot...
夢を束ねて覇道を志す
To unite dreams beneath a banner of conquest.
I praise your efforts.
その意気込みは褒めてやる
But, warriors...
だが強者どもよ 弁えていたか
Did you not understand?
That all dreams eventually disappear, when the dreamer wakes.
夢とはやがてことごとく醒めて消えるのが道理だと
Therefore...
ならばこそ
お前の行く手にオレが立ちはだかるのは必然であったな
It was inevitable that I would stand in your way.
King of Conquerors.
征服王
You will learn of the conclusion to your endless dream.
さあ 見果てぬ夢の結末を知るがいい
このオレが手ずから理を示そう
I'll personally show you how things are.
Here it comes!
来るぞ
さあ目覚めろ『エア』よ
Awaken, Ea!
A stage worthy of you has been set!
お前に相応しき舞台が整った
Look up and behold!
いざ仰げ
Enuma Elish!
天地乖離す開闢の星を
Hold on tight, boy!
坊主 掴まれ
これは
What's this?
あの剣は森羅万象 すべてを崩壊させる対界宝具なのか
Is that sword an anti-world Noble Phantasm capable of destroying all creation?
ライダー
Rider...
そういえば ひとつ聞いておかなければならないことがあったのだ
Come to think of it, there's something I wanted to ask you.
Waver Velvet.
ウェイバー·ベルベットよ 臣として余に仕える気はあるか
Would you like to serve as one of my subjects?
You...
あなたこそ
あなたこそ僕の王だ
You are my king.
I will serve you with everything that I have.
あなたに仕える あなたに尽くす
どうか僕を導いてほしい
Please show me the way...
同じ夢を見させてほしい
Let me see your dream!
うむ 良かろう
Very well.
夢を示すのが王たる余の務め
As a king, it is my duty to present a dream.
そして王の示した夢を見極め
And as one of my subjects, it is your task to see the
dream to the end and speak of it to future generations.
後生に語り継ぐのが 臣たる貴様の務めである
生きろ ウェイバー
Live on, Waver.
すべてを見届け
See it all to the end.
そして生き存えて語るのだ
Live a long life and speak of it.
貴様の王の在り方を
Of your king...
このイスカンダルの疾走を
Of how Iskandar charged forth!
さあ いざ征こうぞ ブケファラス
Now...
Let us go, Bucephalus!
ライダー
Rider!
彼方にこそ栄え在り
Glory lies beyond the horizon.
Challenge it because it is unreachable.
届かぬからこそ挑むのだ
覇道を謳い 覇道を示す
Speak of conquest and demonstrate it.
この背中を見守る臣下のために
For the sake of my subjects who watch behind me!
まったく 貴様
By the gods, you keep pulling out one oddity after another...
次から次へと珍妙なモノを
夢より醒めたか 征服王
Have you awakened from your dream, King of Conquerors?
そうさな
Indeed, I have...
此度の遠征もまた
This campaign has been...
存分に 心躍ったのぅ
...very exciting...
また幾度なりとも挑むがいいぞ 征服王
Feel free to challenge me as many times as you like, King of Conquerors.
ときの果てまで この世界は余さずオレの庭だ
This entire world is my garden until the end of time.
故にオレが保証する
Thus, I can guarantee this.
ここは決して そなたを飽きさせることはない
You will never tire of it.
そりゃあ いいな
That's good to hear...
そうか
Ah, I see...
この胸の高鳴りこそが
The pounding of my heart...
最果ての海の潮騒だったのだ
...was the sound of Ôkeanos' waves...
Boy.
小僧 お前がライダーのマスターか
Are you Rider's Master?
No.
違う 僕はあの人の臣下だ
I am his subject.
そうか
I see.
だが小僧
However, boy, if you really are his loyal subject, you have a duty to avenge your fallen king.
お前が真に忠臣であるならば
亡き王の仇を討つ義務があるはずだが
お前に挑めば 僕は死ぬ
If I challenge you, I will die.
当然だな
Of course.
それはできない
I can't do that.
僕は「生きろ」と命じられた
I was ordered to live on.
忠道大儀である
Your loyalty is splendid.
ゆめ その在り方を損なうな
Never tarnish it.
主は我が魂を蘇らせ
He restoreth my soul.
御名のために我を正道へと導かん
He leadeth me in the paths of righteousness for His Name's sake.
たとえ死の谷を歩むとも
Yea, though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death,
禍を恐るるまじ
I will fear no evil,
主が我と共にあるが故に
for Thou art with me.
貴方の鞭と貴方の杖が私を慰める
Thy rod and Thy staff-they comfort me.
Thou preparest a table before me in the presence of mine enemies.
貴方は我が敵の前で宴を設け
我が頭に油を注ぐ
Thou anointest my head with oil.
My cup runneth over.
杯は溢れ
我に恵みと慈しみを与えるだろう
Surely goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life.
My cup runneth over.
杯は溢れ
Surely goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life.
我に恵みと慈しみを与えるだろう
Episode 23
The Sea at the World's Edge
Doushite sora wa konnani aokute
どうして空はこんなに青くて
Why is the sky so blue?
Nanimo kanashimi wo shiranu you ni
何も悲しみを知らぬように
As if oblivious to sadness
Itsumo tamerawazu ashita e to kuzureochiru
いつも躊躇わず明日へと崩れ落ちる
It crumbles incessantly to make way for a new day
Inochi wa tarinai mama umarete kuru no ne
命は足りないまま生まれてくるのね
I suppose we are born with our lives short
Kakeochita kokoro ni anata ga furete
かけおちた心にあなたが触れて
You have touched my torn heart
Futari de yuku mirai wa kegare no nai tsuyosa de
二人で行く未来は穢れのない強さで
Our future ahead is filled with a pure, unblemished strength
Sora wa takaku kaze wa utau
空は高く 風は歌う
The sky is vast, the wind is melody
Yume wo miteta yorokobi e to
夢を見てた喜びへと
Men will one day come to realize
Hito wa itsuka tadoritsukeru
人はいつか辿り着ける
The joy of chasing after a dream
Kodomo no hitomi de anata wa shinjita
子供の瞳であなたは信じた
With the eyes of a child, you've always had faith
Soba ni iru yo
そばにいるよ
I'll be right beside you
Kooritsuita mori wo nukete
凍りついた森を抜けて
As we pass through the frozen forest
Sono hitomi ga sekai no nageki ni mayowanu you ni
その瞳が世界の嘆きに迷わぬように
So that the world's sorrow will not taint your eyes
私の聖杯を奪うのか
You'd take the Grail from me?!
What are you doing, Saber?!
何のつもりだ セイバー
How helpless you are...
困った御方だ
そんなバカな
That's ridiculous!
It longs for its own life, its own birth!
あれは自らの命を 誕生を望んでいる
お帰りなさい 切嗣
Welcome home, Kiritsugu!
I knew you'd come.
Next Episode
The Last Command Spell
きっと来てくれると思ってた